Guide to University of Maryland Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00228
Cubberley Education Library
University of Maryland (including Baltimore College of Dental Surgery)
1882-1974
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00228
256 item(s)
Located primarily in Baltimore and College Park, Maryland. The College of Medicine of Maryland in Baltimore was chartered in 1807. In 1812 changed name to University of Maryland. Baltimore College of Dental Surgery was chartered in 1840; the Maryland College of Pharmacy in 1841. In 1920 it merged with Maryland State College of Agriculture. Maryland State College was founded in 1856 as Maryland Agricultural College, a land-grant college. Changed name to Maryland State College of Agriculture in 1916. With merger took on name of University of Maryland. Delaware Conference Academy was founded by the Methodist Church in 1886 in Princess Anne, Maryland. Title passed to the state in 1926 and it became part of the University of Maryland in 1948. It became University of Maryland Eastern Shore in 1970. An undergraduate branch campus known as University of Maryland Baltimore County opened at Catonsville in 1966.
Maryland; Land-grant colleges; Dental schools
- Maryland Agricultural College, 1915-16; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1915/16
  Agricultural colleges
- Maryland State College of Agriculture, 1918-1920; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1918/19-1919/20
  - Biennial Report of The Maryland State College of Agriculture and The Maryland State Board of Agriculture, October, 1919; 1 item(s) Report for Oct. 1919
  - Maryland State College: What the College Offers, [1919]; 1 item(s)
- University of Maryland, 1882-1975; 240 item(s) Catalogs for 1920/21-1923/24, 1925/26-1937/38, 1939/40-1940/41, 1942/43, 1944/45-1945/46, 1948/49, 1950/51-1951/52, 1956/57, 1961/63, 1963/65, 1968/70 (vol. 1&2), 1971/73 Baltimore combined catalog for 1962/64
  - University of Maryland School of Medicine, 1882-1967; 43 item(s) Annual circular for 1882/83, 1888/89-1889/90 Announcements for 1911/12, 1914/15-1915/16, 1919/20-1927/28, 1930/31-1949/50, 1963/64,1965/67 Catalogs for 1951/52-1957/59
    Medical colleges
  - Baltimore College of Dental Surgery, 1895-1910; 13 item(s) Catalogs for 1895/96-1906/07, 1909/10
    Dental schools
  - University of Maryland Dental Department, 1911-1912; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1911/12
  - University of Maryland School of Dentistry, 1925-1965; 5 item(s) Catalogs for 1925/26, 1960/61-1962/63, 1964/65
  - University of Maryland Law School, 1902-1975; 50 item(s) Catalogs for 1902-1904, 1911-1913, 1915, 1917, 1926-1929, 1931-1935, 1937-1956, 1957/58-1959/60, 1965/66-1974/75
    Law schools
  - The Centennial Celebration of the Foundation of the University of Maryland, May 30-June 2, 1907; 1 item(s) Memorial Volume published in 1908
  - Biennial (Triennial) Report of the University of Maryland and State Board of Agriculture, 1921-1935; 7 item(s) Biennial reports for 1921, 1924, 1928, 1930, 1933, 1935 Triennial report for 1927
  - University of Maryland: Extension Service (including summary of the work for the past decade), 1924; 1 item(s) Tenth annual report
  - University of Maryland, Agricultural Experiment Station: Undergraduate Academic Achievement and Teaching Performance, September 1965; 1 item(s)
  - University of Maryland: College of Agriculture, 1949-1966; 4 item(s) Bulletins for 1949/50, 1957/58, 1962/64-1964/66
  - University of Maryland: College of Arts and Sciences, 1949-1967; 9 item(s) Catalogs for 1949/50-1950/51, 1953/54, 1956/57-1957/58, 1959/60-1961/62, 1965/67
  - University of Maryland (College Park): Graduate School, 1929-1968; 27 item(s) Announcements for 1929/30-1932/33, 1934/35-1949/50, 1951/52, 1953/54, 1956/57-1957/58, 1959/60, 1964/66-1966/68
    - University of Maryland: Foreign Study Centers-Graduate Year Abroad, 1947-1949; 3 item(s) Foreign Study Bulletins for 1947-1949
    - University of Maryland: European Program, 1950-51; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1950/51
  - University of Maryland: College of Business and Public Administration, 1949-1968; 8 item(s) Catalogs for 1949/50-1950/51, 1954/55, 1957/58, 1959/60-1960/61, 1964/66-1966/68
    Business schools
  - University of Maryland: College of Education, 1946-1966; 8 item(s) Bulletins for 1946/47, 1949/50, 1954/55, 1956/57-1957/58, 1959/60-1960/61, 1964/66
    - The Intern's Handbook: A Guide for Interns in School Administration, May, 1950; 1 item(s)
  - University of Maryland: An Adventure in Learning--A Guide to the Undergraduate Programs, 1958-1970; 6 item(s) Publications for 1958, 1961/62-1964/65, 1969/70
  - University of Maryland: General Information, 1949-1957; 6 item(s) Catalogs for 1949/50-1952/53, 1954/55, 1956/57
  - University of Maryland: Summer School, 1959-1966; 4 item(s) Bulletins for 1959, 1963, 1965-1966
  - University of Maryland: Glenn L. Martin College of Engineering and Aeronautical Sciences, 1949-1955; 3 item(s) Catalogs for 1949/50-1950/51, 1954/55
    Engineering schools
  - University of Maryland: College of Engineering, 1957-1968; 6 item(s) Bulletins for 1957/58, 1959/60-1961/62, 1964/66-1966/68
  - University of Maryland: Physical Education, Recreation and Health, 1949-1968; 4 item(s) Bulletins for 1949/50-1950/51, 1962/64, 1966/68
  - University of Maryland: College of Home Economics, 1949-1966; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1949/50 & 1964/66
  - University of Maryland: A Report of Your State University, 1955-1957; 3 item(s) Reports for 1955-1957
  - University of Maryland at College Park Undergraduate Catalog, 1973-74; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1973/74
  - University of Maryland Eastern Shore, 1970-1973; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1970 & 1972/73